Salvador Hernandez

Phone: 443-683-5400 • Email: s.hernandez5400@gmail.com

Github: clickclickonsal • Website: www.sal.life

Summary

Full stack web developer motivated by hard work and the passion for building things. Valued collaborator with a knack for analyzing data and prioritizing tasks to achieve consistent results. Focused drive for professional excellence and a thirst for knowledge.

Skills

Programming: Ruby, Ruby On Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, underscore.js, backbone.js, Rspec, Sinatra, Active Record, API's, Problem Solving, Agile Methodologies

Software: Mac OSX, Bash, Terminal, Git, Github

Languages: Spanish

Web Development Experience

B Side Shuffle - Washington, DC, November 2014 - January 2015

Freelance Full Stack Web Developer

Website Redesign - https://bsideshuffle.herokuapp.com/

Worked with two UX Designers to redesign the band's website. Responsible for coding and developing site. Technologies Used: Ruby, RoR, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, PostgreSQL, Songkick API, Soundcloud API, Tumblr API, Mini CMS capability added, Animation Effects

Baltimore Hackathon - Baltimore, MD, November 2014

Front-End Developer

Bike Stack is founded by neighbors to help simplify bike parking and make Baltimore a better place to live. Winner of Best Software Team Project Award.

• https://bikestack.herokuapp.com/
Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, Leaflet.js, PostgreSQL, JS, jQuery, AJAX, HTML/CSS, SASS, Bootstrap

General Assembly (GA) - Washington, DC, August 2014 - October 2014

Web Development Immersive Student

Full-stack web development program focused on common best practices in object--oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test--driven development. Developed a portfolio of individually focused and collaboratively focused projects. Projects include:

- PodCloud -- https://podcloud.herokuapp.com
 A web application to help users search for podcasts. Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, ITunes API, PostgreSQL, JS, ¡Query, AJAX, HTML/CSS, SASS, Nokogiri for parsing HTML/XML data
- Docarmation https://github.com/clickclickonsal/docarmation
 A website to help vehicle owners keep track of their maintenance records for their vehicle. Uses the Edmunds API for grabbing vehicle information. Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, Edmunds API, PostgreSQL, JS, jQuery, AJAX, HTML/CSS, SASS
- Survival http://www.runforyour.life/
 A group data visualization project that shows your chances of surviving the zombie apocalypse.
 Technologies used: Ruby, RoR, USA Today API, Google Maps API, RSpec, PostgreSQL, JS, jQuery, AJAX, HTML/CSS, SASS, CSS Sprites, SVG, Type.js

Work Experience

R&H Toyota - Owings Mills, MD, October 2012 - August 2014

Expert Certified Toyota Technician

Tires Plus Total Car Care - West Chester, PA, February 2012 - September 2012

General Service Technician

Universal Technical Institute - West Chester, PA, December 2011 - September 2012 Tutor

Education

General Assembly (GA) - Washington, DC, August 2014 - October 2014

Web Development Immersive

Universal Technical Institute (UTI) – Exton, PA, August 2011 - September 2012